(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026
#Omaru Polka Birthday Festival 2026
新曲のお披露目あり！
New Song Reveal Included!
Glitter of Love
ホロライブ過去最多 ホロメンゲスト10名
Hololive's Record: 10 Guest Members
1/30 21:00~
Jan 30, 21:00~
遥か空響いてる
Echoing in the distant sky,
祈りは奇跡に
prayers turn into miracles.
真っ赤な青に溶けて
Melting into the crimson blue,
流れてく涙の粒
the flowing teardrops.
迷いなく包み込む
Embraced without hesitation,
ぬくもりに出会った
I found warmth.
真っ白な雪のように
Like pure white snow,
どこまでも素直な言葉
words that are honest forever.
鉄の羽根まとった
Clad in iron wings,
僕を動かしてく
it moves me forward.
傷つくたびに
Every time I get hurt,
優しくなれる
I can become kinder.
君のその笑顔だけ
I just want to protect
守り抜きたい
that smile of yours.
願いはひとつ
I have but one wish.
時を超え刻まれた
Carved across time,
悲しみの記憶
memories of sadness.
まっすぐに受け止める
Accepting them straight on,
君は光の天使
you are an angel of light.
あの日胸に灯った
Lit in my heart that day,
永遠の炎
an eternal flame.
深い闇解き放って
Unleashing the deep darkness,
自由の扉開いてく
opening the door to freedom.
強く果てない未来へ
Towards a strong, endless future.
冷たい緑の月に
To the cold green moon,
映し出す心の影
projecting the shadow of my heart.
寂しげに呟いた
Whispering lonely,
君のそばにいたい
"I want to be by your side."
真実と向き合うこと
Facing the truth,
教えてくれた勇気は
the courage you taught me
僕を駆け巡って
runs through me,
夢に目覚めてゆく
awakening to the dream.
触れ合う気持ち
Touching feelings,
離れないように
so they won't separate,
しっかりと抱きしめて
holding them tight.
確かな想い
Certain feelings,
貫いてゆく
piercing through.
銀の海に隠した
Hidden in the silver sea,
空白のページ
a blank page.
君だけが知っている
Only you know,
本当の僕を見せて
show me the real me.
吹き荒れる雑音に
In the raging noise,
生まれゆく誓い
a vow is born.
もう何も怖くはないよ
I'm not afraid of anything anymore.
結んだ視線そらさずに
Without looking away from our gaze.
大切な今始める
Starting the precious 'now'.
君が君でいられる場所
The place where you can be yourself,
幻にさらわれぬように
so you won't be swept away by illusions.
消えない雨の苦しみも
Even the suffering of unceasing rain,
鍵を壊してぶつけてよ
break the lock and throw it at me.
隣にいるから
Because I'm right here,
全てを信じて
believe in everything.
時を超え刻まれた
Carved across time,
悲しみの記憶
memories of sadness.
まっすぐに受け止める
Accepting them straight on,
君は光の天使
you are an angel of light.
あの日胸に灯った
Lit in my heart that day,
永遠の炎
an eternal flame.
時放って
Unleash time,
自由の扉
the door to freedom,
開いてく
opening up.
強く果てない
Strong and endless,
未来へ
to the future!
そうきっとここから
Yes, surely from here,
始まる
it begins!
お待たせみんなー！
Kept you waiting, everyone!
今年もポルカの誕生日が始まったー！
Polka's birthday has started again this year!
タイトルは
The title is...
かっこいい
cool...
Glitter of Love
というわけで
So,
ハッシュタグはこちら
here is the hashtag:
尾丸ポルカ生誕祭
Omaru Polka Birthday Festival...
2026で
2026!
いっぱい
Lots...
and lots...
呟いてねー
tweet about it, okay?
はーい
Okaay!
いや
Man...
今回はテーマがまず
First off, the theme this time is...
愛と勇気と戦う女の子になってまーす
"Girls fighting with love and courage"!
そして
And...
見てくださいこのステージ
look at this stage!
えい！
Hiyah!
はあーすっごい広い！
Wow, it's super huge!
なんとですね
Actually, you see...
広いんですけれどもまず
it's wide, but first...
スクリーンが超おっきい
the screen is super big!
大迫力
High impact!
なんとね
Surprisingly...
いつもの3倍くらい頑張りました
we worked about three times harder than usual.
いや頑張ってもらいましたー
Or rather, I had them work hard!
ありがとうございまーす
Thank you very much!
というわけでですね
So with that said...
ここからゲストの方々が
from here on, guests...
たくさんいらっしゃいます
there are many coming!
もうホロメンだけなら多分尾丸ポルカ史上
Just counting Holo-members, it's probably...
最多のゲスト数だと思っております
the highest number of guests in Omaru Polka history.
それをね、これから
We'll bring that to you...
ノンストップでお送りするので
non-stop from now on, so...
楽しんでいってください
please enjoy it!
というわけで
Alright then...
行くぞー！
let's go!
遺伝子レベルの
Genetic level...
インディペンデンス
Independence.
絶望も希望も
Embrace both...
抱いて
despair and hope.
足掻け命尽きるまで
Struggle until your life runs out.
光と飛沫のキス
A kiss of light and spray.
恋のような
Like love...
虹のバースデイ
a rainbow birthday.
どんな美しき日も
Even on any beautiful day,
何か生まれ
something is born...
何かが死ぬ
and something dies.
せめて歌を
At least, a song...
I love you
世界が酷い地獄だとしても
Even if the world is a cruel hell,
せめて伝えよう
at least, let's convey...
I love you
解放の
Liberation's...
時は来た
time has come.
星降る
Falling stars...
天へと響き飛べ
resound and fly to the heavens!
Very buddy soul
Stardust
そして奇跡は
And miracles are...
待つものじゃなくて
not something you wait for...
その手で作る
but something you make...
ものと吠えろ
with your own hands, so roar!
涙した過去の折り紙を
Turn the origami of the tearful past...
レクイエムにして
into a requiem.
生ある全部の力で
With all the power of life...
輝け Future World
Shine, Future World!
信じ照らせ
Believe and illuminate...
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross!
独りじゃないことを
That you are not alone...
やがて君は知る日の為
for the day you will eventually know.
指先伝う熱度
The heat transmitted through fingertips...
分かち合って
sharing it...
明日に向かう
heading towards tomorrow.
永遠なる空に
In the eternal sky...
I feel you
自由の魂は
The free soul...
殺せはしない
cannot be killed.
不滅なる夢に
In the immortal dream...
I feel you
来世へと
To the next life...
手を握れ
hold my hand.
運命も終曲も
Destiny and the finale...
断ち切る力で
with the power to sever them!
そして重ねた
And the overlapping...
土となって闇を暴く
Becoming earth, exposing the darkness.
駆け抜けたその先には
Beyond where we rushed through,
神様も知らない
Even God doesn't know,
歴史が光り誇る
History shines proudly.
Make a brave heart
この絆 晴天ギャラクシィクロス
This bond is the clear sky Galaxy Cross.
逆光の翼で
With wings of backlight,
Just dream
不死なる炎で
With immortal flames,
Big mission
過去、背負い戦おう
Let's shoulder the past and fight.
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't something to wait for,
その手で作るものと吠えろ
Howl that they are something to create with your own hands.
何度だって何度だって
Again and again, again and again,
立ち上がろうか
Shall we stand up?
生ある全の力で
With all the power of life.
輝け future world
Shine, future world,
信じ照らせ 晴天ギャラクシィクロス
Believe and illuminate, clear sky Galaxy Cross.
Sai sai sai Trio Dreams
Let's sing Let's swing
Let's dance Let's born
Let's smile Let's fly
う～！プリキュア！
Uuu~! Precure!
Sai sai sai Trio Dreams
Let's sing Let's swing
Let's dance Let's born
Let's smile Let's fly
出会い頭 風 世界(未来)
Encounters, wind, world (future).
1+1+1は (無限)
1+1+1 is (infinite).
唇からこぼれる歌は (ララルリララ)
The song spilling from our lips is (Lala-lu-li-lala).
プリズム眩しい光 (マブシャ)
Prism, dazzling light (so bright).
三人寄れば文殊の最高 (最強)
Three people gather, wisdom is supreme (strongest).
始まるさ第一章 (プロローグ)
It's starting, Chapter 1 (Prologue).
Enjoy together
ハミング (ふふ)
Humming (Fufu).
ちょっと臆病 (ぷーぷ)
A little cowardly (Puu-puu).
感傷ね (セッションね)
Sentimental, right? (Session, right?).
Call & Response
型破りでいいよね
Breaking the mold is fine, isn't it?
好きな (好きな) フレーズを
Put your favorite (favorite) phrase,
新音符に夢乗せて
onto new notes carrying dreams.
君 あなたの元へ (for you)
To you, to where you are (for you).
もっともっと輝き合えるね みんな (ラクラ)
We can shine together more and more, everyone (easy-peasy).
瞳 スクリーンに
In your eyes, on the screen,
いつだって 笑顔映し合おう (コミッチュ)
let's always reflect smiles (commu-chu).
君がいるからパワー生まれるよ 今日も
Because you are here, power is born, today as well.
Sai sai sai Trio Dreams
Let's sing Let's swing
Let's dance Let's born
Let's smile Let's fly
う～！プリキュア！
Uuu~! Precure!
Sai sai sai Trio Dreams
Let's sing Let's swing
Let's dance Let's born
Let's smile Let's fly
一緒だから感じるハッピー (ワンニー)
Because we're together I feel happy (One-Two).
1x1x1は (無敵)
1x1x1 is (invincible).
出し惜しみはなしで全部あげたい (フルフルリララ)
Sparing nothing, I want to give it all (Full-full-li-lala).
ハプニングさえもジョイフル (ワンダフル)
Even happenings are joyful (wonderful).
三人寄れば文殊の指南 (次男)
Three people gather, wisdom is instruction (second son).
魅せるよきっと伝説の (ライブ アンコントロール)
We'll charm you, surely, a legendary (Live Uncontrolled).
ゆるみと (ふーふー)
Relaxation and (Fuu-fuu).
没頭 (ぶんぶん)
Immersion (Bun-bun).
称賛 (さんさん)
Praise (San-san).
All genre welcome
Categorize いらないね
We don't need categories, right?
好きだ (好きだ) 思い切り
I love it (love it) with all my might.
3音符の羽広げ
Spread the wings of the three notes.
Heartbeatの奥へ (for you)
To the depths of the heartbeat (for you).
命は輝きでできているの (キラキラ)
Life is made of radiance (sparkle sparkle).
Big screenもはみ出しちゃう
Bursting out even from the big screen,
嬉しいや楽しい (バクラス)
happiness and fun (explosion).
君を知って知らない自分に会えたよ
Knowing you, I met a self I didn't know.
Sai sai sai Trio Dreams
Let's sing Let's swing
Let's dance Let's born
Let's smile Let's fly
君も一緒に！
You too, together!
Let's sing Let's swing
Let's dance Let's born
Let's smile Let's fly
う～！プリキュア！
Uuu~! Precure!
型破りでいいよね
Breaking the mold is fine, isn't it?
好きな
Favorite,
favorite,
フレーズを
phrases.
新音符に
Onto new notes,
夢のせて
carrying dreams.
いつまでも 笑顔映し合おう
Let's reflect our smiles on each other forever.
君がいるから Power 生まれるよ今日も
Because you are here, power is born today too.
Let's Sing! Let's Dance! Let's Pump! Let's Smile! Let's Fly!
Woo!
Let's Sing! Let's Sing! Let's Sing!
Let's Pump! Let's Pump! Let's Pump! Let's Fly!
暗闇の真ん中 まっすぐな眼差し
In the middle of the darkness, a straightforward gaze.
立ち上がる姿 ちゃんと見ていたよ
I was watching you stand up properly.
閉じ込められそうな 心を奮い立たせ
Rousing a heart that seemed about to be locked away.
収まりきらない 輝きを放つ
Releasing a radiance that cannot be contained.
秘めたる胸の奥 焼き付いた眩しさは
The dazzle burned deep within my hidden chest.
それだけでもう 自由になる 待っていて
Just that alone sets me free. Wait for me.
取り戻したい
I want to take it back.
光の世界
The world of light.
その笑顔 (勇気)
That smile (Courage).
涙 (夢 希望の兆し)
Tears (Dreams, a sign of hope).
君と明日を
Together with you tomorrow.
願う力で
With the power of wishing.
生まれる
Is born.
私達のハーモニー
Our harmony.
響け
Resound!
それでも暗闇が 訪れてしまうもの
Even so, darkness is something that visits.
惑わされないで 君は君だから
Don't be led astray, because you are you.
私が出会えた日々が ハートを輝かせる
The days I met you make my heart shine.
1人じゃないこと 気付かせてくれる
Making me realize that I am not alone.
抱えきれないほどの 「ありがとう」の代わりに
Instead of a 'Thank you' too big to hold,
鍵をかけて ひとつになる 受け止めて
Lock it up, become one, accept it.
取り戻すんだ
We will take it back.
光の未来
The future of light.
今 熱い (想い)
Now, passionate (Feelings).
繋ぐ (声 叶えに行くよ)
Connect (Voices, going to grant them).
君と一緒に
Together with you.
願える奇跡
A miracle we can wish for.
重ねて
Overlapping.
広がっていくハーモニー
An expanding harmony.
目覚める時が来たね
The time to awaken has come.
本当の自分になる
Becoming my true self.
満ちる運命
A fulfilling destiny.
取り戻したい
I want to take it back.
光の世界
The world of light.
その笑顔 (勇気)
That smile (Courage).
涙 (夢 希望の兆し)
Tears (Dreams, a sign of hope).
君と明日を
Together with you tomorrow.
願う力で
With the power of wishing.
生まれる
Is born.
私達のハーモニー
Our harmony.
響け
Resound!
Day by day 日に日に募るの乙女心
Day by day, a maiden's heart grows stronger day by day.
三角フラスコ
A triangle flask...
眼鏡の大人しい人
and a quiet person with glasses.
カッコよくはない
He's not exactly cool,
だけど優しい
but he's kind.
いつも頼れる彼
He's someone I can always rely on.
オタク恋愛相談の帰り道
On the way home from discussing our otaku love lives,
何だって話せる親友の女の子
with my female best friend whom I can tell anything.
スポーツ万能
She's great at sports,
勉強も出来て
good at studying too,
女子力マックスです
and her girl power is maxed out.
どこにでもある
It's a story you find anywhere,
よくあること
a very common thing.
急に彼女が
Suddenly, she said to me...
あのね実は私
"Hey, actually...
好きな人がいるのって
...I have someone I like."
ちょマジで！？
Wait, seriously!?
三角形
Triangle,
三角形の恋は気まぐれ
triangular love is whimsical.
一瞬で
In an instant,
一瞬で崩れるバランス
in an instant, the balance collapses.
ベタな漫画みたいなフラグ
A flag straight out of a clichéd manga,
まさかね自分が
I can't believe I'd set one up myself,
立てちゃうなんて残念すぎます
it's just too unfortunate.
三角形
Triangle,
三角形の恋は不安定
triangular love is unstable.
なんちゃって
Just kidding,
なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
this category can't be settled with "just kidding".
恋と友情ゆらゆらめいて
Love and friendship, swaying back and forth.
なんか青春しちゃいます
I feel like I'm living my youth.
私困っちゃいます
I'm totally in a bind.
完璧でお似合いすぎるわ勝てこない
They're perfect and match so well, I can't win.
悔しいけどとかそんなんじゃなくて本心
It's not sour grapes or anything, it's my true feeling.
ていうかすでに応援モード
I mean, I'm already in support mode.
むしろ清々しい
It's actually refreshing.
だけど彼女は
But she...
不思議な顔
...has a strange look on her face.
真剣な目で
With serious eyes, she said...
そうじゃなくて私
"That's not it...
あなたが好きなのゴメンって
...I like YOU. Sorry."
ちょマジで！？
Wait, seriously!?
三角形
Triangle,
三角形の恋は気まぐれ
triangular love is whimsical.
一瞬で
In an instant,
一瞬で崩れるバランス
in an instant, the balance collapses.
私
Me...
あなた
...you...
彼女と私
...her and me?
超絶複雑百合展開は想定外です
A super complex Yuri development was not in my plans!
三角形
Triangle,
三角形の恋は不安定
triangular love is unstable.
なんちゃって
Just kidding,
なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
this category can't be settled with "just kidding".
解けないパズル
An unsolvable puzzle.
与えたもうた神よ
Oh God who gave this to me...
うなんちゃいます
I'm groaning in agony.
私悩んじゃいます
I'm so worried.
あーもう！すごいヤバイ！
Ah geez! This is super bad!
見たよ？
I saw it?
見たけど…って
I saw it but... wait,
そういう意味じゃなくて
that's not what I mean!
だって女の子同士だし
But we're both girls!
女神様どうしたらいいの？
Goddess, what should I do?
私どうしたいの？
What do I want to do?
Help me!
なんか変だ
Something's weird.
愛に国境も年も性別も関係ない
Love has no borders, age, or gender!
けど、けど、けど
But, but, but...
三角形
Triangle,
三角形の恋は気まぐれ
triangular love is whimsical.
一瞬で
In an instant,
一瞬で崩れるバランス
in an instant, the balance collapses.
普通の恋
I was dreaming of...
夢見てたのに
...a normal romance.
ノーマル設定の私じゃ
For someone with 'normal' settings like me,
ちょっと無理ゲーすぎます
this game is a bit too impossible.
三角形
Triangle,
三角形の恋は不安定
triangular love is unstable.
なんちゃって
Just kidding,
なんちゃってじゃ済まないカテゴリー
this category can't be settled with "just kidding".
彼女のこと
If I could...
好きになれたら
...fall in love with her...
なんて妄想しちゃいます
...I'm starting to have delusions like that.
私どうかしてます
There's something wrong with me.
煌々と続くショートショート
Brightly shining, the short stories continue.
喪失は絶対で意図的
The loss is absolute and intentional.
今夜はリンカーネーション 悲しみが
Tonight is a reincarnation, where sadness...
混沌の子守唄 歌ってるよ
...is singing a chaotic lullaby.
運命に理由があるのならば
If there is a reason for this fate,
全てを賭けてみたいの
I want to bet everything on it.
貴方を守りたい
I want to protect you.
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
I can fly higher than anywhere.
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can become stronger and stronger, no matter how far.
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle that we met.
火に開くは不死鳥の羽根 解いて
Unfurl the wings of the phoenix that open in the fire.
貴方のドグマ
Your dogma.
高く高く眼差し 泣きたくなるの
High, so high, your gaze makes me want to cry.
Flashback flashback 振り解け
Flashback, flashback, shake it off.
Asset 挑み続けろ
Asset, keep on challenging.
飄々と佇むホットスポット
Standing aloof at the hot spot.
私が必要でしょ
You need me, don't you?
今夜はリンカーネーション 正しさが
Tonight is a reincarnation, where righteousness...
焦れったい最前線に押し出すよ
...pushes us to the frustrating front lines.
運命に理由があるのならば
If there is a reason for this fate,
優しい世界をあげたい
I want to give you a gentle world.
貴方を包むわ
I will wrap around you.
どこまでも速く射抜くわ
I will pierce through faster than anywhere.
どこまでも熱く熱く焦がすわ
I will burn hotter and hotter, no matter how far.
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle that we met.
火に開くは不死鳥の羽根 解いて
Unfurl the wings of the phoenix that open in the fire.
貴方のドグマ
Your dogma.
高く高く肩越し 光を見せて
High, so high, show me the light over my shoulder.
Flashback flashback 許さない
Flashback, flashback, I won't forgive.
Regret 進み続けろ
Regret, keep moving forward.
尽きるまで
Until I burn out...
側にいると鼓動が速くて 眩暈がする
...when I'm by your side, my heart races and I get dizzy.
全て捧げる もう決めたの
I'll dedicate everything, I've already decided...
最後のチャンスだから
...because this is the last chance.
もう離さない
I won't let go anymore.
貴方に燃ゆる未来の風
Ride the wind of the future...
跨って行け
...that burns for you.
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
I can fly higher than anywhere.
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
I can become stronger and stronger, no matter how far.
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle that we met.
闇をも望めば輝きにするから
If you desire it, I'll turn even the darkness into radiance.
火に開くは不死鳥の羽根 解いて
Unfurl the wings of the phoenix that open in the fire.
貴方のドグマ
Your dogma.
高く高く眼差し 泣きたくなるの
High, so high, your gaze makes me want to cry.
Flashback flashback 振り解け
Flashback, flashback, shake it off.
Asset 挑み続けろ
Asset, keep on challenging.
高く高く肩越し 光を見せて
High, so high, show me the light over my shoulder.
Flashback flashback 許さない
Flashback, flashback, I won't forgive.
Regret 進み続けろ
Regret, keep moving forward.
神様に恋をしてた頃は
When I was in love with God,
こんな別れが
I never thought
来るとは思って
such a parting
なかったよ
would ever come.
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I can never touch you again,
せめて最後に
then at least, for the last time,
もう一度抱きしめて
I wanted you to hold me
欲しかったよ
just one more time.
It's long long goodbye
さよなら さよなら
Goodbye, goodbye,
何度だって
no matter how many times,
自分に無情に
I heartlessly tell
言い聞かせて
myself over and over.
手を振るのは優しさだよね
Waving goodbye is an act of kindness, isn't it?
今 強さが欲しい
I want strength right now.
貴方に出会い STAR 輝いて
I met you, and the STAR shone bright.
アタシが生まれて
And I was born.
愛すればこそ
Because I love,
愛あればこそ
because there is love,
希望のない奇跡を待ってどうなるの
What's the use of waiting for a hopeless miracle?
涙に滲む
Blurred by my tears,
星の瞬きは gone
the twinkling of the stars is gone.
忘れないよ
I won't forget,
貴方のぬくもりも
not your warmth,
その優しさも
nor your kindness,
全て包んでくれた両手も
nor the hands that wrapped everything in love.
It's long long goodbye
さよなら さよなら
Goodbye, goodbye,
愛しい人
my beloved.
貴方がいたから
Because you were there,
歩いてこれた
I could walk this far.
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよね
I wasn't alone, was I?
今 答えが欲しい
I want an answer now.
燃えるような流星捕まえて
Catch a burning meteor,
火を灯して
and light a fire.
愛していたい
I want to keep loving,
愛されてたい
I want to be loved.
冷えた身体ひとつで世界はどうなるの
What will become of the world with just one cold body?
張り続けてた虚勢が
The bluff I kept up
溶けてく long for
is melting away, long for.
どうしてだろう
Why is it?
涙溢れて
Tears are overflowing,
止められない
and I can't stop them.
貴方に出会い STAR 輝いて
I met you, and the STAR shone bright.
アタシが生まれて
And I was born.
愛すればこそ
Because I love,
愛あればこそ
because there is love,
希望のない奇跡を待ってどうなるの
What's the use of waiting for a hopeless miracle?
涙に滲む
Blurred by my tears...
もし生まれ変わって
If we are reborn,
また巡り会えるなら
and can meet again,
その時もきっと
even then, surely,
アタシを見つけ出して
please find me.
もう二度と離さないで
Never let me go again,
捕まえてて
hold on to me tight.
…じゃないと
...that it isn't [a miracle],
囁いてほしい Planet
I want you to whisper, 'Planet'.
聖なる瞳が
If your holy eyes
痛みを映したら
Reflect the pain,
振り向いてごらん
Turn around and look,
情熱放つ Trick
A trick that unleashes passion.
崩れる足元
With the ground crumbling beneath us,
二人は戻れない
The two of us can't go back.
差し伸べた手をほどかないで
Don't let go of my outstretched hand.
消えるよまた
They disappear again,
優しい日々が
Those gentle days.
思い出を汚すのは
I won't allow anyone
許せない
To tarnish our memories.
ここは裏切りの楽園(ティル・ナ・ノーグ)
This is a paradise of betrayal.
さまよう心の果てに
At the end of a wandering heart,
光を求めて
Seeking the light,
祈る言葉届けあなたに
May my prayer reach you.
囚われの羽が
These captive wings
遥かな空へと向かう
Head towards the distant sky.
信じたいよ私たち
I want to believe that we are...
孤独じゃない
...not alone.
分かり合う (求め合う)
Understanding each other (Seeking each other)
絆の中 (離れない)
In this bond (Never parting)
離さない
I won't let go,
始まる Destiny
The beginning Destiny.
新たな願いに
When a new wish
鎖解ける時
Unlocks the chains,
休ませてくれる
Let me rest
深い眠りに
In a deep sleep.
僅かな希望が
A faint hope
私を強くする
Makes me stronger.
温もりに触れてみたいから
Because I want to feel your warmth.
蘇れば
If it revives,
儚き命
This fleeting life.
繰り返す愛しさが 導いた
Guided by repeating affection.
胸に歌声の調べ
A melody of singing in my heart.
流れる世界の終わり
At the flowing end of the world,
諦めはしない
I won't give up.
今が繋ぐ明日探そう
Let's find the tomorrow that 'now' connects to.
ちぎれ舞う羽は
These torn, dancing wings
未来の空にも向かう
Head towards the future sky too.
忘れないで私たち
Don't forget,
一つの Crystal
We are a single Crystal.
輝いて (私が)
Shining bright (I am)
割れないのよ
Unbreakable.
離さない (離れない)
Not letting go (Never parting)
誓いの Destiny
The Destiny of our vow.
消えるよまた
They disappear again,
優しい日々が
Those gentle days.
思い出を汚すのは
I won't allow anyone
許せない
To tarnish our memories.
ここは裏切りの楽園(ティル・ナ・ノーグ)
This is a paradise of betrayal.
さまよう心の果てに
At the end of a wandering heart,
光を求めて
Seeking the light,
祈る言葉届けあなたに
May my prayer reach you.
囚われの羽が
These captive wings
遥かな空へと向かう
Head towards the distant sky.
信じたいよ私たち
I want to believe that we are...
孤独じゃない
...not alone.
分かり合う (求め合う)
Understanding each other (Seeking each other)
絆の中 (離れない)
In this bond (Never parting)
Wow wow wow wow...
やっとみんな会えたね
Finally met everyone, huh!
Don't stop! Non stop! The finish!
Wow wow wow wow...
高ぶった全力走りたい
I want to run with all my hyped-up power
芝生の砂跡 君の追い切りメニュー
Traces in the turf, your training menu
Turn! Turn!
声出せ叫べ
Let out your voice, shout!
Wow wow wow wow...
それで？
And then?
Hai! Hai! Hai!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
高ぶった全力上がりたい
I want to rise with all my hyped-up power
譲れない夢の途中
In the middle of a dream I can't yield
Wow wow
走れよここから最高のストーリー
Run! Starting here, the best story
Oh oh oh...
嗚呼 焦がれた地平線
Ah, the horizon I yearned for
語り合ったメモリー
The memories we talked about
もうドキドキもときめきも
My pounding heart and fluttering pulse
抑えられない たまんない
I can't suppress it, it's unbearable
熱いハラハラが止まらない
The hot suspense won't stop
君と
With you
走り競いゴール目指し
Racing, competing, aiming for the goal
遥か響け届けミュージック
Echo far away, reach them, music
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Always, always, always, always, these feelings
夢がきっと叶うなら
If dreams will surely come true
あの日君に感じた
That day, what I felt in you
何かを信じて
Believing in that something
春も夏も秋も冬も
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter
越え願い焦がれ走れ
Overcome, wish, yearn, run!
勝利へ
To victory!
Don't stop! Non stop! The finish!
Wow wow wow wow...
高ぶった全力弾けたい
I want to burst with all my hyped-up power
大出会い決意絆になった
Big encounter, determination, became a bond
Hand up! Hand up!
本気で叫べ
Shout seriously!
Wow wow wow wow...
それで？
And then?
Hai! Hai! Hai!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
高ぶった全力笑いたい
I want to laugh with all my hyped-up power
タフのど真ん中
Right in the middle of the toughness
Wow wow
リアルにここから上昇ストーリー
For real, from here on, a rising story
Oh oh oh...
嗚呼 駆け抜けた日々
Ah, the days we ran through
語り合ったグローリー
The glory we talked about
今 答えたい生きてると
I want to answer now, that I'm alive
背中押す声 熱くなれ
Voices pushing my back, get hot!
夢は夢のまま終われない
Dreams can't end as just dreams
君と
With you
未来描きゴール目指し
Sketching the future, aiming for the goal
狙え挑め掴め Winning
Aim, challenge, seize the Winning
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Always, always, always, always, these feelings
夢はきっと叶うから
Because dreams will surely come true
あの日君が流した
That day, what you shed
涙も信じて
Believe in those tears too
雨も風も雲も闇も
Rain, wind, clouds, and darkness
越え願い焦がれ走れ
Overcome, wish, yearn, run!
勝利へ
To victory!
揺るぎない覚悟決して
Determined with unwavering resolve
一つ二つ共に綴る記録
One by one, the records we write together
背中に迫る迷い振り払え
Shake off the hesitation closing in on my back
今の自分追い越すだけ
Just overtaking my current self
勝ちたい
I want to win
君と勝ちたい!
I want to win with you!
未来描きゴール目指し
Sketching the future, aiming for the goal
狙え挑め掴め Winning
Aim, challenge, seize the Winning
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Always, always, always, always, these feelings
夢はきっと叶うから
Because dreams will surely come true
あの日君が流した
That day, what you shed
涙も信じて
Believe in those tears too
春も夏も秋も冬も
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter
雨も風も雲も闇も
Rain, wind, clouds, and darkness
越え願い焦がれ走れ
Overcome, wish, yearn, run!
勝利へ
To victory!
君と
With you
走り競いゴール目指し
Racing, competing, aiming for the goal
遥か響け届けミュージック
Echo far away, reach them, music
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い
Always, always, always, always, these feelings
夢がきっと叶うなら
If dreams will surely come true
あの日君に感じた
That day, what I felt in you
何かを信じて
Believing in that something
It's finally the true end
I'm ready for... my destiny
I'm ready for... STARTING OVER
やっと幕を下ろせた 最期の瞬間まで
Finally let the curtain fall, until the very last moment
わたしは精一杯に わたしをやりきった
I gave it my all, I lived as myself to the fullest
終演の続きは 誰も知らなくていい
No one needs to know what happens after the show ends
涙を置いて 新しい旅に出よう
Leave the tears behind, let's set out on a new journey
熱狂はあなたを選ぶ 違う結末だっただけ
The frenzy chooses you, it was just a different ending
同じ愛になれなかった Destiny
We couldn't become the same love, Destiny
これまでの全てを 差し出すような愛だった
It was a love where I offered up everything until now
世界の意味が変わるくらいに 肯定された気がしたんだ
I felt affirmed enough to change the meaning of the world
何気なさの中で 気づけた最初の奇跡が
The first miracle I realized amidst the casualness
あなたでよかった わたしでよかった
I'm glad it was you, I'm glad it was me
心から思えたよ
I could feel that from the bottom of my heart
ずっと遠い未来も ちゃんと覚えていよう
Even in the far distant future, let's remember properly
自分の抱きしめ方 明日の願いかた
How to embrace myself, how to wish for tomorrow
あなたががいなくても わたしの片隅で
Even if you aren't here, in a corner of my heart
優しい光 消えたりしないとわかる
I know the gentle light won't vanish
今はまだ手を振れるほど 道は別れたばかりで
Right now, we've only just parted ways, close enough to still wave
後ろ髪に風を感じながら
While feeling the wind on the back of my hair
それまでの全てが あなたに出会うためだった
Everything until then was to meet you
どの瞬間もムダじゃないこと 本当の意味で知れたから
Because I learned the true meaning that no moment was a waste
次の曲がり角も 自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose the next turning point with my own style
いつかに繋がる 新しい一歩
A new step that connects to someday
信じて歩き出そう
Let's believe and start walking
心から誰かを愛せた あの日々は
Those days when I could love someone from my heart
間違いなくわたしの Destiny Ah,
Were undoubtedly my Destiny, Ah,
これまでの全てが 新しい力をくれる
Everything until now gives me new power
どの瞬間もムダじゃないなら 何が起きても大丈夫だから
If no moment is wasted, then I'll be okay no matter what happens
次の物語も 自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose the next story with my own style too
いつかに繋がる わたしのはじまり
My beginning that connects to someday
信じて歩き出そう
Let's believe and start walking
いつかに繋がる わたしのはじまり 信じて歩き出そう
Connecting to someday, my beginning. Believe and walk forward.
再び幕は上がる
The curtain rises again.
聴いていただいたのは、新曲の『STARTING OVER』でした！
What you just heard was my new song, "STARTING OVER"!
はい、新年一発目、新曲の初披露ということで
Yes, first thing in the New Year, revealing a new song...
ぬるっとね、新曲をやってしまったんですが
I just kind of casually performed a new song there.
平成感のある、懐かしみの感じの楽曲を歌わせていただいたんですけれども
I got to sing a song with a nostalgic Heisei-era vibe.
このあとこの曲が、24時から…あと数時間後か、24時からですね
After this, starting at midnight... just a few hours from now...
1月30日の24時から、配信リリースされます！
It will be released for streaming at midnight on January 30th!
たくさん聴いてください！
Please listen to it a lot!
今年もね、たくさんオリ曲出していきたいです
I want to release lots of original songs this year too.
そしてそして、もうMCがね、実は最後なので
Also, this is actually the last MC segment.
この配信の後には、メンバー限定の配信もあるのでよろしくお願いします
There will be a members-only stream after this, so please check it out.
よしよしよし！グッズ紹介！
Alright, alright! Goods introduction!
えー、ここには同期のねぽらぼ大集合ということで
Uh, my genmates NePoLaBo are all gathered here...
ねぽらぼ、集まれ〜！
NePoLaBo, assemble!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
初めて呼びました、どうも〜
First time calling you guys over. Hello!
ポルカチャンネル初です！
First time on Polka's channel!
誕生日！誕生日！
Birthday! Birthday!
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ここまでが流れでございます
That was the planned flow.
ずっと待ってたから
We were waiting the whole time.
グッズをね、紹介させていただきたいと思います
I'd like to introduce the merchandise.
なんか後ろで失礼ながらリアクションなどを各々取っていただいて
Please excuse me while they react in the background.
ガヤすか
Are we the background noise?
ガヤだガヤだ！
It's the peanut gallery!
というわけで、尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念グッズ2026！
So, Omaru Polka Birthday Goods 2026!
ラインナップはこちら！ドン！
Here is the lineup! Bam!
ドン！
Bam!
素晴らしい、今回もラインナップが揃っております
Wonderful, we have a great lineup again this time.
あれ？なんかちょっと
Huh? Something's a little...
あれ？あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh? Huh?
なんか盛ってます？
Are you padding it?
盛ってませんよ！
I am not padding it!
というわけで、まず一つ一つフォーカスしていきましょう
Anyway, let's focus on them one by one.
まずはこちら！
First is this!
ポルカの「はじめての抱き枕カバー」となっております
It's Polka's "First Dakimakura Cover".
すごーい、可愛いー！
Wow! So cute!
ちょっとパンツ履いてません？
Wait, is she not wearing panties?
丸出しじゃないですか？
Isn't it all out in the open?
それ部屋着だよー！
That's roomwear!
部屋着って、だって寝る時だってこういう部屋着だろ！
Roomwear... I mean, you wear this kind of stuff to sleep, right?!
人のチャンネルだからって言いたい放題しちゃって！
Saying whatever you want just because it's someone else's channel!
お前シャツで寝たらしわ付くぞ！
If you sleep in a shirt, it'll get wrinkled!
写真撮影用かもしれないですもん！
It might be for a photoshoot!
というわけで、初めて抱き枕カバー出します
So, I'm releasing my first dakimakura cover.
表が通常衣装で、裏は彼シャツになってます
The front is the standard outfit, and the back is a 'boyfriend shirt'.
彼シャツ〜！
Boyfriend shirt~!
続きましてドン！
Moving on, bam!
こちら、歴代衣装のポルカランダムラバーストラップです
These are random rubber straps of Polka's past outfits.
かわいいー！
So cute!
これまでの衣装のラバーストラップ、こちらnoimimi先生に描いていただきました
Rubber straps of previous outfits, drawn by noimimi-sensei.
え、めっちゃいいじゃんこれ
Eh, these are super good.
どの衣装が出るかお楽しみです
Look forward to seeing which outfit you get.
続きましてこちら！
Next up is this!
どれもこれも宝物、思い出バインダー！
Every one of them a treasure, the Memory Binder!
おお、いいね！
Oh, nice!
最近みんなも特典でチェキ風のブロマイドカード出したりしてるから
Lately everyone's been releasing cheki-style bromide cards as bonuses...
そういうの入れられたり
So you can put those in there.
あとはホロカも入るサイズになっていますので
It's also sized to fit holo-cards.
ぜひぜひいろんな思い出しまってください
Please store all your various memories in it.
はい、そして続きましてはこちら
Yes, and next is this.
ポルカのしっぽキーホルダー
Polka's Tail Keychain.
かわいー！
Cute!
一周して流行ってるからね、ポルカのしっぽ型のキーホルダー
It's come full circle and is trendy now, a keychain shaped like Polka's tail.
確かに確かに。平成レトロみたいな感じだ
True, true. It has a Heisei retro feel.
はい、こちらも付けてください
Yes, please attach this to something too.
そしてボイスも出てます。ボイスはこちら！ジャン！
Also, there's voice content. The voice is this! Ta-da!
ASMRボイスです
It's an ASMR Voice.
まあ、『彼シャツポルカ』という…ちょっとタイトルもなんか…
Well... "Boyfriend Shirt Polka"... the title is a bit...
狙ってるじゃん。えっちコンロ点火？
You're aiming for it. Turning on the lewd stove?
やめてよ！チャッカマンやめて！
Stop it! Stop with the fire starter!
なんで今日同期呼んじゃったんだろうって一瞬思った今、恥ずかしくなってきた
For a second I wondered why I invited my genmates today, I'm getting embarrassed.
添い寝ASMRというか、抱き枕カバーとイラストの関係があるシナリオになってます
It's a sleeping-together ASMR... the scenario relates to the dakimakura cover illustration.
おー、なるほどー
Oh, I see.
ね、みんなお待たせしました、フルセット購入特典となっております、こちら！
And thank you for waiting everyone, the Full Set Purchase Bonus, here!
チェキ風ブロマイドカード、数量限定が直筆メッセージ、箔押し複製サインになっております！
Cheki-style Bromide Card. Limited quantities will have a handwritten message and foil-stamped duplicate signature!
通常が箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りでございます
The regular version comes with the foil-stamped duplicate signature and message.
フルセットぜひぜひ買っていただいた方には、特典ボイスとして、すやすやポルカの添い寝ボイスというか…
For those who buy the full set, there's a bonus voice... a sleeping Polka voice...
ちょっとそういったボイスに合わせて、こっちもASMRになってまーす。
Matching that kind of voice, this side has also become ASMR.
よろしくお願いしまーす。
Please treat me well.
恥ずかしいな...みんなとやるのこれ。
This is embarrassing... doing this with everyone.
なんか、エッチな女になっちまったって。
Like, I've become a lewd woman.
すいません...いいじゃない。
Sorry... isn't it fine?
新年もね、えーと皆さん改めてこれからもよろしくお願いします。
For the New Year too, um, everyone, once again, please treat us well from now on.
お願いしまーす！
Please treat us well!
というわけでね、今日はみんなで最後一緒に歌うために呼んできたということで、準備してきまーす！
So, today I invited everyone to sing the last song together, so we'll get ready!
行ってきまーす！
We're off!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
おー！じゃあ...ポチッとな！
Yeah! Then... *click*!
脚本は捨てちゃおうか
Shall we throw away the script?
指しカット焼き付けよう
Let's burn in the insert cut,
アドリブの熱いパフォーマンス
with a hot ad-lib performance.
やめられない飛び出して
Can't stop, jump out,
壮大なステージに響く
resounding on the grand stage.
特別なストーリー
A special story.
瞼の裏には
Behind the eyelids,
星空のメモリー
memories of the starry sky.
等身大の愛を込めて
With life-sized love,
想像を超える世界へ
to a world beyond imagination.
誰も知らないでしょ
No one knows it, right?
Are you ready?
どんな未来か見に行こうよ
Let's go see what kind of future it is.
なんて自由だ笑っちゃうよね
It's so free, makes you laugh, doesn't it?
ホログラムよりも先へ
Beyond the hologram.
誰だって置いてかないよ
I won't leave anyone behind.
ご覧喝采が呼んでいる
Look, the applause is calling.
ステップからパッと照らす
Suddenly shining from the step,
人生のスポットライト
life's spotlight.
薔薇色のプレミアショー
A rose-colored premiere show.
ここが特等席よ
This is the best seat.
こじらせ日和
A perfect day for complications,
天気次第のエチュード
an etude depending on the weather.
まるで御伽噺
Just like a fairy tale,
捕まえてよ
catch me.
待って ほら 待って
Wait, look, wait.
予想のできない展開に
In an unpredictable development,
ステージは揺れる
the stage shakes.
特別なストーリー
A special story.
耳を澄ましたら
If you listen closely,
次の合図のハーモニー
the harmony of the next signal.
浮かぶふわふわな空想
Floating fluffy fantasies.
暴走底なしの本能
Runaway bottomless instincts.
全て知りたいでしょ
You want to know everything, right?
Hey guys! 叫べ
Hey guys! Shout!
気分は最高？ 最高！
Feeling the best? The best!
Come on! もっと叫べ
Come on! Shout more!
気分は最高？ 最高！
Feeling the best? The best!
ポルカ終わるか？
Will Polka end?
終わらない！It's showtime!
It won't end! It's showtime!
繋いだ手離さないでなんてね
'Don't let go of my hand,' just kidding.
どうしたって重たくなっちゃって困るわ
No matter what, it gets heavy and I'm in trouble.
いつの日かエピローグを一緒に綴ろう
Someday, let's weave the epilogue together.
きっと約束よ Life goes on!
It's a promise, for sure! Life goes on!
どんな未来か見に行こうよ
Let's go see what kind of future it is.
なんて自由だ笑っちゃうよね
It's so free, makes you laugh, doesn't it?
ホログラムよりも先へ
Beyond the hologram.
夢のような花舞台に
On this dream-like flower stage,
感情を馳せたら
if we let our feelings run wild,
ステップからパッと照らす
suddenly shining from the step,
人生のスポットライト
life's spotlight.
薔薇色のプレミアショー
A rose-colored premiere show.
どこへだって添い遂げたい
I want to be with you wherever we go.
ここが特等席よ
This is the best seat.
あんたにゃもったいない
You don't deserve it.
あたしゃ本当NICE BODY
I truly have a NICE BODY,
自分で言う位
Enough to say it myself.
タダじゃないじゃない
It's not for free, not for free.
熱けりゃ冷ませばいい
If it's hot, just cool it down.
寂しけりゃ EVERY BODY BODY BODY
If you're lonely, EVERY BODY BODY BODY.
誰にもわからない
No one understands,
恋愛っていつ火がつくのか
When the fire of love will ignite.
DYNAMITE
恋はDYNAMITE
Love is DYNAMITE.
どんなに不景気だって
No matter how bad the economy is,
恋はインフレーション
Love is inflation.
こんなに優しくされちゃ
If you treat me this kindly,
みだら
It's lewd.
明るい未来に
For a bright future,
就職希望だわ
I hope to find employment.
Wow wow wow wow
日本の未来は
Japan's future is,
Wow wow wow wow
世界がうらやむ
Envied by the world.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love, shall we?
Wow wow wow wow
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
なんだか物足りない
Somehow unsatisfied.
どこにいたって愛してて欲しいわ
Wherever I am, I want you to love me.
自分で伝えるの
I'll convey it myself.
恥ずかしいじゃない
It's embarrassing, isn't it?
理想の二人が
The ideal couple,
憧れよ EVERY BODY BODY BODY
Is what we admire, EVERY BODY BODY BODY.
誰しも気づいてない
No one has noticed,
恋愛って夢の落とし穴
Love is a trap of dreams.
MYSTERY
恋はMYSTERY
Love is MYSTERY.
そんなに不自然だって
Even if it's that unnatural,
恋のインサイダー
Love's insider.
それでも上手にされちゃ
Even if you handle me so well,
あらわ
Exposed.
幸せ来る日も
Days when happiness comes,
キャンセル待ちなど
Waiting for cancellations, etc.
Wow wow wow wow
あんたの笑顔は
Your smile is,
Wow wow wow wow
世界がうらやむ
Envied by the world.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah
夢があるじゃないか
There are dreams, aren't there?
Wow wow wow wow
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
Fuwafuwa fuwafuwa!
Love love love machine
Love love love station
Love love love factory
Love! Love is so wonderful
Yeah!
Wow wow wow wow
日本の未来は
Japan's future is,
Wow wow wow wow
世界がうらやむ
Envied by the world.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love, shall we?
Wow wow wow wow
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
座員のみんなも
The Zain members too,
あんたも私も
You too, and me too,
みんなも社長さんも
Everyone, and the president too!
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
Love machine.
新曲のお披露目あり！ Glitter of Love
New song reveal! 'Glitter of Love'
ポルカのライブ過去最多 ★ ホロメンゲスト10名
Polka's biggest live yet! ★ 10 Holomem guests
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026 1/30 21:00~
#OmaruPolkaBirthday2026 1/30 21:00~